As you've seen, there are thousands of tools that help
如你所见 市面上有上千种工具可以帮助企业
companies collect data across a wide variety of subjects.
收集各类数据
Tools make it easier for us to not only collect data,
工具不但使得数据的收集变得简单
but they give us a jump start by recommending the actions that we might want to take.
而且它们也会给予我们一些行动上的建议 让我们更容易开始
Many tools these days are using machine learning to
现在很多工具都使用了机器学习来
detect patterns and mine giant source of data to
发现和挖掘庞大数据源里的规律
automatically identify the most actionable areas of
自动识别在哪些方面做出行动
your business to achieve the goal that you've established.
可以帮助你的业务实现目标
Now the tools are helpful,
工具很有用
but they don't do all of the work.
但是它们并不能完成所有的工作
So I want to spend some time looking at
接下来 我会花点时间讲一些常用工具
a few common tools by the type of data they collect and report on,
以及它们收集和汇报的数据类型
so that you can gain better insights into how to leverage this data and how to start
这样的话 你就可以更了解如何利用好这些数据 以及如何
cross referencing your datasets to deliver on what is most actionable for you.
比较不同来源的数据集 从而发现最有效的行动计划
Now the most common tools will typically focus on a particular data area such as
常用工具通常都只关注某一个特定领域的数据 比如
social media and web monitoring or search
社交媒体 网站
analytics or audience analysis or even content analysis.
搜索分析 受众分析 甚至内容分析
When you start to evaluate tools,
刚开始选择工具的时候
a great platform to take a look at all of this is G2 Crowd.
推荐使用 G2 Crowd 一个众包企业软件评价平台 非常棒
There you can see all of the tools available for what you're trying to accomplish,
在这里 你可以看到能帮助达成你的目标的各种工具
you'll see how they rank,
它们的排名
you can read reviews and determine if
你也可以阅读评价 来确定某款工具
that tool based on the features it has will meet your requirements.
是否有符合你的要求的性能
Now when you start looking at analytical tools,
当你选择分析工具时
I want you to consider several items.
我希望你可以考虑以下几个方面
First is data capture.
第一个是数据抓取
There is no tool that is going to offer 100 percent data capture.
没有任何一个工具可以抓取到 100% 的数据
Every tool have their sweet spot for the channel metrics that it's gathering.
每一个工具都会针对某个渠道指标来进行抓取
As the tools have matured,
随着工具的迭代
many of them seem to be pretty good across most channels,
很多工具现在已经可以兼容不同的渠道了
but some tools are going to be really better at making sense of particular areas such
但是还是有一些工具在分析特定渠道或者领域的时候 表现会特别突出
as blogs from around the web or data on very specific forums such as Reddit.
比如 网络上的博客 或者像 Reddit 的特定论坛数据
The channels that you want to be measuring when you're
在初始阶段 你需要衡量的渠道
starting out are going to be where you think most
应该是你认为你的目标群体或者
of your audiences or where most of
大多数目标群体
the audience that you want to be capturing is spending their time.
会关注或者花时间在那里的渠道
From here, you need to think about how these platforms integrate with other data sources.
然后你需要考虑这些平台如何与其他数据源融合
Can they talk to one another?
它们的数据可以互相交换吗？
If you're using multiple tools,
如果你选用了多个工具
you want to understand if they can easily share that data back and forth.
你会需要知道这些工具是否可以便捷地共享数据
The easier that they share data,
共享数据的方式越简单
the easier your job will be.
你就越轻松
Next, we need to evaluate cost.
接下来 我们要评估费用
How much can you spend?
你的预算是多少？
A lot of tools are getting very expensive and it can be
现在很多工具收费都很贵
really exciting to see all of these great features that a tool provides.
如果能使用到某个工具的所有很棒的功能 那肯定是很好的
But you have to zoom out and think about whether
但是你要抽离出来 想一下是否值得花钱
the insights you gain are going to be worth what you're spending.
取得这些洞察
If you can't take actions based on
如果工具提供的数据 不能促使你做出某些行动
that data that improve what you're earning enough to cover the tool,
从而不能提高收入 来覆盖工具的使用成本
then there's no point in using that tool.
那就没意思了
You also need to factor in the cost of changing platforms.
你也需要考虑到换平台\工具产生的费用
If you're using a tool now and you want to move to a different tool,
比如当前你在使用某个工具 然后你需要换到另一个工具
there is a significant cost in development,
开发成本是很贵的
time, and training to move to that new tool.
还有时间 以及迁移培训的成本
Also, it's important to evaluate whether the tool is easy to use on a mobile device.
同时 一个工具是否能在手机上使用 这点也很重要
When you're on the go and you're always wanting to be looking at that data every day,
如果你总是在外面跑 然后又想随时关注数据
it should be fairly easy to look at your summary analytics on your phone.
这时候如果能在手机上看到总结报告 那就很方便了
Another really important but often overlooked piece of
另一个很重要但又被常常忽视的点是
a value in a tool is whether or not it has an API access.
它有没有 API 接口
This is the way the developers can gather data out of the tool so that
开发人员会需要从工具里提取数据
you can apply custom learnings say within your own data warehouse.
这样你才能基于自己的数据仓库 来应用定制化的分析
You can use an API to pull down your own queries
你可以使用 API 来执行问询、抓取数据
to gather the insights that you need for your specific objectives.
帮助你实现你的分析目标
Another thing that I like to evaluate is whether the tool has
我喜欢评估的另一个方面是这个工具是否有
a consistent and meaningful user interface.
稳定的、有意义的用户界面
If the tool is hard to use or it's not laid out in a meaningful way,
如果这个工具特别难用 或者界面不清晰
you're not going to use it all that often and you're not going to find
你就不会常用它 自然也不会常用到它提供的信息
the information that you need to make that tool worth what you're spending.
这样就不划算了
Another piece to evaluate is your workflow.
再然后 还有考虑这个工具是否有利于你的工作流程
How easy is it for you to engage other people from your team?
比如 如果要跨团队合作 这个工具是否能支持？
Can you pass the insights that you're finding off easily?
你是否能轻松地把你的发现传达给其他人？
Can you share that data?
数据是否可以分享？
Is the data in real time?
数据是不是实时的？
Can you download it?
可以下载吗？
How easy is it to move and migrate that data off of the platform?
是否可以很方便地将数据从这个工具中迁移出？
Another interesting aspect is the historical data.
还有一个很有意思的方面 是历史数据
Sometimes when you sign up for a tool,
有时候如果你注册了某个工具
they can bring in historical data about your brand
他们也会提供关于你的品牌的历史数据
even if you hadn't signed up for the tool and started monitoring for it.
即使你之前没有注册 没有使用它来监测
Now every tool has a different window by which they can look back,
每一个工具都有关于历史数据的不同功能
so you'll need to evaluate what makes sense for your needs.
所以你会需要决定哪个对你来说最有用
Another really important piece is how customizable the dashboard is.
另一个非常重要的考虑因素 是数据面板是否可定制化
Just because the way the tool is setup for
工具本身有个自带的界面
their needs doesn't necessarily make sense for your needs.
不代表它就符合你的需求
Everybody likes to look at data in a different way and put
每个人关注数据的习惯都是不一样的
metrics next to one another in a way that's actionable for you.
如果处理指标的展示方式 也是不一样的
So it's helpful when you can customize those dashboards.
所以如果面板能定制 就很有帮助
Also you need to consider the cross-functional use of a tool.
同时 也要考虑一个工具的跨职能性
A lot of tools are going to fit into an ecosystem beyond marketing.
很多工具后续可能会需要适应一个比营销更为庞大的生态体系
You may have PR, legal and customer support all sharing in this tool.
比如可能 PR、法务、客服可能都会共享这个工具
Then we need to think about what happens as the company grows?
然后我们还要考虑 如果公司业务持续发展呢？
Is the data in this tool portable?
这个工具里的数据是否可以顺利迁移出？
Perhaps we're using one tool but after a certain size,
比如目前我们在使用某个工具 但是业务达到一定规模后
it's not going to make sense to keep using that tool.
我们需要换工具
How are we going to get that data out and is it possible?
这时候如果把数据转移出来？是否可以操作？
Now when you look on the web and read about these tools,
如果你查阅这些工具的官网
honestly a lot of them sound very similar.
你会发现好多信息都非常类似
They seem to use a lot of generic language to help
很多内容好像都在用模板语言
explain what their tool does and all of the benefits.
来解释这些工具的作用以及优势
Be sure that you're evaluating tools based on your specific requirements.
所以一定要根据你的具体需求来选取工具
Make a list of the questions that you're trying to answer
把你想关注的业务问题列成一张清单
and be sure that the tool can give you those insights.
然后确保这个工具能给你答案
Be sure to use resources like G2 crowd to refine those options.
一定要用类似 G2 crowd 这样的平台来进一步筛选
Take your time, do the research,
不要着急 深入研究下
and you'll be well on your way to finding the perfect tools for your needs.
相信你会找到最符合你的需求的工具的！